Welcome back.
Let's talk about the process groups.
I know you've already seen this you already know the process groups but this is some really important
information for your exam and I want to walk through the process groups and the processes are the in
jail all this up.
Let's talk about these process groups and processes and how it will relate to your exam.
OK.
These processes are arranged in process groups as you can see across the top we have the initiating
planning executing monitoring and controlling and closing them down the first column are our knowledge
areas that correspond with the different chapters of the Pinback guide the intersection of a knowledge
area and a process group is where you go find individual processes.
So let's work through these.
We have initiating.
We have to develop the project charter and identify stakeholders planning.
There are 24 develop the project management plan plan scope management collect requirements define scope
create the WTS then we have plan schedule management defined activities sequence activities estimate
activity durations develop schedule Plan cost management estimate cost determine budget plan quality
management plan resource management estimate activity resources plan communications management plan
risk management identify risk perform qualitative and then we have perform quantitative risk analysis
plan risk responses plan procurement management plan stakeholder engagement.
Next step we have executing there are 10 executing processes direct directed manage the project work
manage project knowledge manage quality acquire resources develop team manage team manage communications
implement risk response's conduct procurements and manage stakeholder engagement then monitoring and
controlling.
We have 12 processes monitoring control the project work perform integrated change control validate
scope control scope control schedule control cost control quality control resources monitor communications
monitor risk control procurements bonnet Churr stakeholder engagement and then there's just one process
in closing and that's to close the project or phase when you are learning these processes throughout
this course especially as you get into those last few days before you go into Passhe year exam.
I want you to pay more attention to initiating event closing and then executing because there's a larger
distribution of questions to processes than you have in planning and monitoring and controlling.
So really really no initiating closing executing in that order and that will help you out in your exam.
All right good job I told you it was quick.
Just a quick review of these process groups keep moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.